



t. 203 644 4827

e. fratino.a@gmail.com

w. adamfratino.com

github.com/88mpg codepen.io/88mpg

肖

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I have a thirst for knowledge and experience. My passions have varied over time, but my desire to learn is consistent. This allows me to effectively contribute when working with others, and provides me with continued motivation when working alone.

The combination of my strong technical theory and my appreciation for aesthetics has provided the foundation of my career path, fueling my desire to bridge the gap between functional technology and aesthetic design.

EDUCATION



- School of Visual Arts Sept 2009 Jan 2013 Bachelors of Fine Arts - 3.5 GPA Graphic Design New York, New York
- Northeastern Univeristy Sept 2003 May 2005 Creative Writing & Journalism Boston, Massachusetts
- School of Audio Engineering Nov 2006 May 2007 Audio Engineering & Digital Production New York, New York

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS



1. DEVELOPMENT

HTML & CSS (SCSS, LESS) JavaScript (ES6, Babel, Webpack) Preprocessors (Gulp, Grunt, PostCSS) MVC Frameworks (React, Vue) Responsive Design

Cross-Browser Best Practices Version Control (Github, Terminal)

2. DESIGN

Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator Sketch, InVision (Zeplin)



PROFESSIONAL OBJECTIVE



My immediate employment objective is to be a front-end web developer for an innovative company that embraces both cutting-edge technology and lasting aesthetics.

I would thrive as a member of a team that values communication and collaboration when working towards a common goal.

WORK EXPERIENCE



Rokkan February 2017 - Present

Senior Front End Developer, New York City

Took over as sole front end developer for an enterprise telecommunications client's OBD product. Rebuilt site from scratch to strip unnecessary dependencies (jQuery, Foundation), instead using ES6, Babel, Webpack, PostCSS. Worked with back-end development to convert static HTML to AEM components.

The Barbarian Group August 2014 - February 2017

Senior Front End Developer, New York City

Full-stack development on larger incremental projects, creating custom boilerplates for our team, major bug fixes, and building new global properties for an enterprise electronics retailer.

Global Point New York Sept 2013 - June 2014

Senior Fullstack Developer, New York City

Sole developer, fullstack web development for a small creative agency. Typical process included client interfacing, translating flat artwork into functional wireframes, full development, cross-browser testing, production setup and deployment.

Freelance Web Development Apr 2008 - July 2013

Various full-stack projects ranging from small- and medium-sized businesses to independent creatives. Includes custom Wordpress themes and plugins and static builds while studying design at the School of Visual Arts.

REFERENCES

Both professional and personal references upon request.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION



Development samples: 88MPG on Github & CodePen The place I call home on the internet: adamfratino.com